Guide to the Real Estate Office, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Real Estate Office, Yale University, records
1943-1991
RU 522
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
41.5
(45 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, memoranda, and photographs documenting the operations and activities of the Yale Real Estate Office. Materials include legal documents and correspondence concerning real estate investments, real estate accounts and records, New Haven property files, statements, bills and receipts.
Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 5-D (YRG 5-D), Investment and insurance records of Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, memoranda, and photographs documenting the operations and activities of the Yale Real Estate Office. Materials include legal documents and correspondence concerning real estate investments, real estate accounts and records, New Haven property files, statements, bills and receipts.
Real property -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Universities and colleges -- Finance; New Haven (Conn.); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
- Photographs of New Haven properties, 1969-1985; Accession 19ND-A-508
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Arrangement
  Photographs are arranged alphabetically by name of building (if available) or by address.
- Records, 1943-1960; Accession 1961-A-005
- Account records, 1979-1980; Accession 1980-A-030
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016
- Records, 1964-1980; Accession 1981-A-048
- Records, 1951-1981; Accession 1982-A-044
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017
- Records concerning New Haven properties, circa 1956-1981; Accession 1982-A-045
  - 1201 Chapel Street, 1978 (Box 1)
- Records, 1977-1981; Accession 1982-A-046
- Records, 1967-1983; Accession 1983-A-078
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019
  - 16 Edgewood Avenue (Box 1)
  - 175 Saint Ronan Street (Box 1)
  - 163-165 Mansfield Street (Box 1)
  - 179 Mansfield Street (Box 1)
  - 187 Mansfield Street (Box 1)
  - 165-182 Highland Street: Ivy Manor (Box 2)
  - 17 Broadway, Whitlocks: correspondence (Box 4)
- Records, 1982-1983; Accession 1984-A-047
  - 16 Edgewood Avenue - 068A, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - 165-182 Highland Street 585 Prospect Street (IVY Manor) - 080F, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - 163-165 Mansfield Street - 097A, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - 179 Mansfield Street - 095F, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - 187 Mansfield Street - 103F, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
- Records, 1958-1984; Accession 1985-A-034
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2020
  - 194-198 York Street - Correspondence, 1958-1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Records, 1975-1984; Accession 1985-A-035
  - Mellon Gallery: Chapel-High (Kusterer) 44 High and 1082-1090 Chapel (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mellon Gallery-Perlroth Properties (Lomas and Nettleton) 46 High and 1074-1080 Chapel (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 163-165 Mansfield 097A (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - 179 Mansfield 095F (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - 187 Mansf ield 103F (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - 16 Edgewood 068A (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Yale Center for British Art: Mellon Gallery
  - Eastern Properties Services
- Case files of the Yale University Mortgage Program, 1985-1991; Accession 2007-A-008
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2067